Finding Aid for William G. Price papers, 1967 to 1971
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
William G. Price papers 1967-1971
Price, William George, Jr.
0.5 linear feet
2011018 Aa 2
Graduate student at University of Michigan from 1966 to 1972 involved in student government and campus organizations. Papers consist primarily of administrative documents from and materials regarding the governance of the various organizations in which Price was active, including the University Cooperative, Graduate Assembly, Student Government Council, Student Relations Committee, and University Bookstore and University Cellar.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Material received in September 2010 (Donor no. 10433 ).
No further additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is open to research.
William G. Price was a graduate student in nuclear engineering at the University of Michigan from 1967 to 1972. He completed his dissertation in 1972 on Variational Theory and Flux Synthesis With Applications to Fast Reactor Spectrum Calculations. While a student, Price served as Executive Vice President of the Graduate Assembly from 1969 to 1970, and acted as the first President of the University Cooperative, a consumer cooperative affiliated with the Credit Union. Price also served on the Committee on Policy, Central Student Data File, as well as the first Board of the Student Bookstore, Inc. (later University Cellar) and the Student Relations Committee from 1969 to 1970.
The papers document the development and activities of various University of Michigan student governance groups and campus organizations from 1967 to 1971. The files are divided into six series: Central Student Data Files, Co-op, Graduate Assembly, Student Relations Committee, University Bookstore, Inc., and Student Government Council. The series represent the original order of the materials.
Subjects:
Consumer cooperatives--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Price, William George.; University Cellar.; University of Michigan. Graduate Assembly.; University of Michigan. Student Government Council.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.
- Central Student Data Files, 1968-1970
  The Central Student Data Files include documents relating to a controversy in 1968-1969 regarding the University's policies on student information retention and accessibility. The papers encompass the efforts on the part of the Student Relations Committee, the Student Government Council, and the Student Affairs Committee to petition the University to amend these policies. The files include administrative items, correspondence and publicity documents.
  - Administration, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Publicity, 1967-1970 (Box 1)
- Co-op, 1969-1970
  The Co-op series contains documents regarding the establishment of the University Cooperative in 1969, developed in parallel with the University Bookstore, with some association with the Credit Union. The Co-op served as a means to purchase and negotiate various discounts within the Ann Arbor community. The series includes correspondence, meeting minutes, memos, publicity, and reports and proposals.
  - Correspondence, 1969-1070 (Box 1)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1969-1070 (Box 1)
  - Memos, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Publicity, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Reports and proposals, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
- Graduate Assembly 1968-1971
  The Graduate Assembly series includes administrative and publicity documenting a group which was created to organize a student government for the Rackham School of Graduate Studies, circa 1971. The Graduate Student Council became the Graduate Assembly, and there was a question as to the legitimacy of its formation vis-à-vis the general student governance. The series includes administrative documents, as well as publicity.
  - Administration, 1968-1971 (Box 1)
  - Publicity, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
- Student Relations Committee, 1968-1970
  The Student Relations Committee series reflects the work of s committee of the Faculty Senate. Documentation represent some of the work concerning disciplinary action to take away scholarships from students arrested during various protests. The papers cover the period between 1969 and 1970, during which Price was a representative to the Committee from the Graduate Assembly. The series includes various administrative papers and meeting notes.
  - Administration, 1968-1970, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Meeting notes, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
- University Bookstore, Inc., 1069=1971
  The University Bookstore, Inc. series is comprised of papers relating to the establishment of and actions on the part of the board of the bookstore circa 1970 to 1971. Price was on the bookstore's governing board. Material includes correspondence, meeting notes and budgets, and memos, reports, bylaws, and various organizational polices. The bookstore was later renamed as University Cellar.
  - Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - Meeting Notes and Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Memos, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Reports, Bylaws, and Policies, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
- Student Government Council, 1969
  The papers contained within the Student Government Council series document policies and governance within the organization.
  - Policies and Governance, 1969 (Box 1)